Finding aid to the Elder Women Oral History Project oral histories SSC.MS.00766
Sophia Smith Collection
Elder Women Oral History Project oral histories
2010-2013
Sophia Smith Collection
Winborn, Rebecca
SSC.MS.00766
0.833 linear feet (1 container plus digital files)
This collection exists because Rebecca Winborn was motivated by a desire to incorporate elder women into a "working, living archive" of their generational experiences. It includes interview transcripts, audio recordings (in the form of one cassette tape, twelve CDs, and digital files), photographs of all participants, and, in the case of one participant who passed away before the end of the project, materials from a funeral and correspondence with the family.
Biographical Note
Rebecca Winborn was motivated by a desire to incorporate elder women into a "working, living archive" of their generational experiences. She opted to interview women over the age of 80, many of whom were her friends'mothers, members of her church, or in her own family. These interviews took place in 1-2 hour installments over the course of roughly one year per participant. The audio recordings were preserved alongside images of the elder women and typed transcripts. Interviewees are primarily white, middle class, and scattered across the American Northeast, Midwest and Northwest. Topics and historical events include the Great Depression, World War II, health and disability, experiences of aging, retirement, the Unitarian Church, religion generally, addiction, motherhood, and family.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use with following restrictions on access: Do not post the oral histories online.
Scope and Contents
The Elder Women's Oral History Project oral histories includes interview transcripts, audio recordings (in the form of one cassette tape, twelve CDs, and digital files), photographs of all participants, and, in the case of one participant who passed away before the end of the project, materials from a funeral and correspondence with the family.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Rebecca Winborn on 2/11/2016.
Oral histories; Oral history; Aged women -- History -- Sources; Aged women -- United States; Darlington, Jeanne; Dratch, Jeanne; Farmer, Shirley; Fleck, Melba; Geller, Judy; Jones, Judith; Mercurio, Priscilla; Metcalf, Hope Rogers; Nussbaum, Sylvia; Richard, Adrienne; Rubin, Lilian; Sibbison, Rita; Thompson, Alice C.; Winborn, Rebecca; Levy, Patricia Barry; Digital files; Transcripts
- 2016 accession, 2010-2013; Accession 2016-S-0014
  - Transcripts, photographs, CDs (12), and audio cassette (1), 2010-2013 (Box 1)
    - Jeanne Darlington, 2012 (Box 1)
    - Claire Dratch, 2011-2012 (Box 1)
    - Shirley Farmer, 2012 (Box 1)
    - Melba Fleck, 2011-2012 (Box 1)
    - Judy Geller, 2012-2013 (Box 1)
    - Judith Jones, 2012-2013 (Box 1)
    - Priscilla Mercurio, 2011 (Box 1)
    - Hope Rogers Metcalf, 2011 (Box 1)
    - Sylvia Nussbaum, 2010-2011 (Box 1)
    - Adrienne Richard, 2010-2011 (Box 1)
    - Lilian Rubin, 2012 (Box 1)
    - Rita Sibbison, 2012 (Box 1)
    - Alice Thompson, 2011-2012 (Box 1)
  - Digital files (list available) (Box 1)